# Fanyi Xiao

CONTACT Information 2078 Academic Surge University of California, Davis Davis, CA 95616, USA WWW: fanyix.cs.ucdavis.edu Mobile: 949-491-2293

E-mail: fyxiao@ucdavis.edu

RESEARCH INTERESTS I am interested in computer vision and machine learning, with a focus on designing models to effectively learn from videos in order to better understand videos (with tasks like recognition, detection and segmentation) and beyond (e.g., images and sounds).

#### EDUCATION

### University of California Davis, Computer Science Dept., Davis, CA, USA

Ph.D. student, Computer Science

• Advisor: Prof. Yong Jae Lee

## Carnegie Mellon University, Robotics Institute, Pittsburgh, PA, USA

M.S., Robotics, 2014

• Advisors: Prof. Martial Hebert and Prof. Yaser Sheikh

• Thesis: Model Recommendation for Large Scale Exemplar-based Object Detection

## Central South University, Computer Science Department, Changsha, China

B.S., Computer Science, 2012

• Thesis: Facial Expression Analysis with Active Appearance Model

#### Publications

- [1] Fanyi Xiao, Yong Jae Lee, Kristen Grauman, Jitendra Malik, and Christoph Feichtenhofer. Audiovisual slowfast networks for video recognition. 2019. (Under submission).
- [2] Daniel Bolya, Chong Zhou, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee. Yolact++: Better real-time instance segmentation. 2019. (Under submission).
- [3] Fanyi Xiao, Haotian Liu, and Yong Jae Lee. Identity from here, pose from there: Self-supervised disentanglement and generation of objects using unlabeled videos. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019.
- [4] Daniel Bolya, Chong Zhou, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee. Yolact: Real-time instance segmentation. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2019. (Oral presentation).
- [5] Xitong Yang, Xiaodong Yang, Ming-Yu Liu, Fanyi Xiao, Larry S Davis, and Jan Kautz. Step: Spatio-temporal progressive learning for video action detection. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2019.
- [6] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Video object detection with an aligned spatial-temporal memory. In European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2018.
- [7] Wenjian Hu, Krishna Kumar Singh\*, Fanyi Xiao\*, Jinyoung Han, Chen-Nee Chuah, and Yong Jae Lee (\* equal contribution). Who will share my image? predicting the content diffusion path in online social networks. In ACM International Conference on Web Search and Data Mining (WSDM), 2018.
- [8] Fanyi Xiao, Leonid Sigal, and Yong Jae Lee. Weakly-supervised visual grounding of phrases with linguistic structures. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2017.

- [9] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Track and segment: An iterative unsupervised approach for video object proposals. In *Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition* (CVPR), 2016. (Spotlight presentation).
- [10] Krishna Singh, Fanyi Xiao, and Yong Jae Lee. Track and transfer: Watching videos to simulate strong human supervision for weakly-supervised object detection. In Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2016.
- [11] Fanyi Xiao and Yong Jae Lee. Discovering the spatial extent of relative attributes. In *International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV)*, 2015. (Oral presentation).
- [12] Fanyi Xiao and Martial Hebert. Efficient model evaluation with bilinear separation model. In Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2015.
- [13] Zhiding Yu, Chunjing Xu, Deyu Meng, Fanyi Xiao, Wenbo Liu, and Jianzhuang Liu. Transitive distance clustering with k-means duality. In *International Conference on Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR)*, 2014.
- [14] Iljoo Baek, Taylor Stine, Denver Dash, Fanyi Xiao, Yaser Ajmal Sheikh, Yair Movshovitz-Attias, Mei Chen, Martial Hebert, and Takeo Kanade. Physical querying with multi-modal sensing. In Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2014.

#### AWARDS

- Google Cloud Platform Research Grant, 2019
- Best Graduate Researcher Award, CS Dept. of UC Davis, 2018
- Azure Research Award, Microsoft, 2017
- Graduate Fellowship, UC Davis, 2015
- AWS Research Grant, Amazon Web Services, Inc., 2015
- Excellent Undergraduate Thesis, CSU, 2012
- Top Grade Scholarship (University-wide highest honor, 0.8%), CSU, 2010
- Sunward Scholarship (0.4%), Sunward Corporation, 2010
- 1st Grade Scholarship (6%), CSU, 2009
- National Scholarship (1%), Ministry of Education of China, 2009

#### EXPERIENCE

## Facebook AI Research (FAIR), Menlo Park, CA

Summer Intern

June 2019 - Nov 2019

• Work on Audiovisual video understanding (recognition, detection and representation learning). [Under submission]

#### NVIDIA Research, Santa Clara, CA

Summer Intern

July 2017 - Oct 2017

• Work on action detection in videos. Proposed an iterative method for detecting action tubes. [CVPR 2019]

# Disney Research, Pittsburgh, PA

Summer Intern

June 2016 - Sept 2016

 Work on weakly supervised vision-language alignment (more specifically, producing segmentation masks for free-form language inputs) by exploiting linguistic structure. [CVPR 2017]

#### SKILLS

- Programming: Python, C/C++, Lua, MATLAB, Java
- Misc: PyTorch, Torch7, Caffe, Caffe2, Linux, LATEX

# RELATED GRADUATE COURSES

- CMU: Computer Vision / Machine Learning / Convex Optimization Math Fundamentals for Robotics / Learning-based Methods in Vision Mechanics of Manipulation
- UC Davis: Visual Recognition

#### SERVICE

- Reviewer, Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR), 2018-20
- Reviewer, European Conference on Computer Vision (ECCV), 2020
- Reviewer, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV), 2019
- Program Committee, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence (AAAI), 2019
- Reviewer, Asian Conference on Computer Vision (ACCV), 2018
- Reviewer, Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV), 2015-18